<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Keaven M. Anderson</title>
    <link>https://keaven.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Keaven M. Anderson</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://keaven.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>gsDesign2 1.1.1, new preprint, and practice award</title>
      <link>https://keaven.github.io/blog/gsdesign2-1-1-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://keaven.github.io/blog/gsdesign2-1-1-1/</guid>
      <description>We are excited to announce the release of gsDesign2 1.1.1. This is a maintenance update that brings both new features and improvements. Built upon the gsDesign experience, gsDesign2 is an R package designed for group sequential clinical trial design under non-proportional hazards.&#xA;You can install gsDesign2 from CRAN with:&#xA;install.packages(&amp;quot;gsDesign2&amp;quot;) What’s new in gsDesign2 1.1.1 Highlights of this release include the new method for generating RTF table outputs, more rigorous input checking, and performance optimizations.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>simtrial is on CRAN</title>
      <link>https://keaven.github.io/blog/simtrial-0-3-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://keaven.github.io/blog/simtrial-0-3-2/</guid>
      <description>We are excited to announce the first release of simtrial on CRAN. simtrial is a fast and extensible clinical trial simulation framework for time-to-event endpoints.&#xA;You can install simtrial from CRAN with:&#xA;install.packages(&amp;quot;simtrial&amp;quot;) A clinical trial simulation framework simtrial is intended to be a general purpose tool for simulating fixed, group sequential, or adaptive clinical trials. There are several design principles for the framework to create a coherent workflow while allowing maximum flexibility:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>gsDesign 3.6.0</title>
      <link>https://keaven.github.io/blog/gsdesign-3-6-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://keaven.github.io/blog/gsdesign-3-6-0/</guid>
      <description>We are thrilled to announce the release of gsDesign 3.6.0. gsDesign makes it easy to create group sequential clinical trial designs in R. gsDesign also offers a web interface to enable both design creation/updates without coding and code generation to reproduce the design.&#xA;You can install gsDesign from CRAN with:&#xA;install.packages(&amp;quot;gsDesign&amp;quot;) What’s new in gsDesign 3.6.0 Time-to-event endpoint design with calendar timing of analyses We added a gsSurvCalendar() function to enable group sequential design for time-to-event outcomes using calendar specification of interim analysis timing.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Books</title>
      <link>https://keaven.github.io/books/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://keaven.github.io/books/</guid>
      <description>Clinical trial design Group Sequential Design Web Interface&#xA;Technical manual of the gsDesign web interface&#xA;gsDesign Technical Manual&#xA;Design and analyze group sequential trials with the R package gsDesign&#xA;Group Sequential Design Under Non-Proportional Hazards&#xA;Deming Conference course on group sequential design, December 6, 2021&#xA;Clinical trial submission R for Clinical Study Reports and Submission&#xA;Prepare tables, listings, and figures for clinical study report and submission&#xA;Contributed book chapters Sample Size Estimation and Power Analysis: Time to Event Data</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>https://keaven.github.io/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://keaven.github.io/publications/</guid>
      <description>Google Scholar profile | Download BibTeX file&#xA;2023 | 2022 | 2021 | 2020 | 2018 | 2016 | 2015 | 2014 | 2012 | 2011 | 2010 | 2009 | 2008 | 2007 | 2006 | 2004 | 2003 | 2002 | 2001 | 2000 | 1999 | 1998 | 1997 | 1996 | 1995 | 1994 | 1993 | 1992 | 1991 | 1990 | 1989 | 1988 | 1987 | 1986 | 1985 | 1984 | 1983 | 1982 | 1980</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Selected talks</title>
      <link>https://keaven.github.io/talks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://keaven.github.io/talks/</guid>
      <description>2022 Some industry trials over the last 30 years: personal experience and challenges 2022 ASA Biopharmaceutical Section Regulatory-Industry Statistics Workshop, Rockville, MD. Grammar of Group Sequential Design MCP Conference 2022: The 12th International Conference on Multiple Comparison Procedures, Bremen, Germany. Joint Statistical Meetings, Washington, DC. (recording) 2021 Group Sequential Design Under Non-Proportional Hazards (short course, slides). The 77th Annual Deming Conference on Applied Statistics. R for Clinical Study Reports and Submission (workshop, slides).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Software</title>
      <link>https://keaven.github.io/software/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://keaven.github.io/software/</guid>
      <description>gsDesign: group sequential design&#xA;CRAN | GitHub | Documentation&#xA;gsDesign Explorer: group sequential design web interface&#xA;rinpharma mirror | gsdesign mirror | Documentation&#xA;gsDesign2: group sequential design under non-proportional hazards&#xA;CRAN | GitHub | Documentation&#xA;simtrial: clinical trial simulation&#xA;CRAN | GitHub | Documentation&#xA;gMCPLite: lightweight graph-based multiple comparison procedures&#xA;CRAN | GitHub | Documentation&#xA;gMCPShiny: Shiny app for graphical multiplicity control&#xA;GitHub | Documentation&#xA;wpgsd: weighted parametric group sequential design</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
