<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blogs on Keaven M. Anderson</title>
    <link>https://keaven.github.io/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blogs on Keaven M. Anderson</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://keaven.github.io/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Delayed effect asymptotic approximations and simulation</title>
      <link>https://keaven.github.io/blog/delayed-effect-simulation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://keaven.github.io/blog/delayed-effect-simulation/</guid>
      <description>Overview&#xD;Computing preliminaries&#xD;Design assumptions&#xD;Fixed design&#xD;Simulation of fixed design&#xD;Group sequential design&#xD;Same design with weighted logrank&#xD;Accumulation of events and average treatment effect over time&#xD;Alternate analysis timing and \(\alpha\)-spending strategies&#xD;Simulation to verify operating characteristics&#xD;Simulate a single trial and perform tests&#xD;Simulate multiple trials in parallel&#xD;Summary&#xD;Session info&#xD;References&#xD;Expect delays. Photo by Erik Mclean.&#xD;Overview&#xD;We consider asymptotic approximations and corresponding simulations for&#xD;group sequential designs with delayed treatment effects.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Smoothing hazard rates and survival curves with bshazard</title>
      <link>https://keaven.github.io/blog/bshazard/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://keaven.github.io/blog/bshazard/</guid>
      <description>National Aquarium Denmark, Den Blå Planet. Photo by Sandro Katalina. Introduction The R package bshazard (Rebora, Salim, and Reilly 2014) has been available on CRAN since 2014. It might be useful where there is interest in where smoothed hazard rates cross. When there is excess in one arm early and excess in the other arm late, the time at which (smoothed) hazard rates cross can come well before the time when Kaplan-Meier survival curves cross.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>gsDesign2 1.1.1, new preprint, and practice award</title>
      <link>https://keaven.github.io/blog/gsdesign2-1-1-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://keaven.github.io/blog/gsdesign2-1-1-1/</guid>
      <description>We are excited to announce the release of gsDesign2 1.1.1. This is a maintenance update that brings both new features and improvements. Built upon the gsDesign experience, gsDesign2 is an R package designed for group sequential clinical trial design under non-proportional hazards.&#xA;You can install gsDesign2 from CRAN with:&#xA;install.packages(&amp;quot;gsDesign2&amp;quot;) What’s new in gsDesign2 1.1.1 Highlights of this release include the new method for generating RTF table outputs, more rigorous input checking, and performance optimizations.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>simtrial is on CRAN</title>
      <link>https://keaven.github.io/blog/simtrial-0-3-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://keaven.github.io/blog/simtrial-0-3-2/</guid>
      <description>We are excited to announce the first release of simtrial on CRAN. simtrial is a fast and extensible clinical trial simulation framework for time-to-event endpoints.&#xA;You can install simtrial from CRAN with:&#xA;install.packages(&amp;quot;simtrial&amp;quot;) A clinical trial simulation framework simtrial is intended to be a general purpose tool for simulating fixed, group sequential, or adaptive clinical trials. There are several design principles for the framework to create a coherent workflow while allowing maximum flexibility:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>gsDesign 3.6.0</title>
      <link>https://keaven.github.io/blog/gsdesign-3-6-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://keaven.github.io/blog/gsdesign-3-6-0/</guid>
      <description>We are thrilled to announce the release of gsDesign 3.6.0. gsDesign makes it easy to create group sequential clinical trial designs in R. gsDesign also offers a web interface to enable both design creation/updates without coding and code generation to reproduce the design.&#xA;You can install gsDesign from CRAN with:&#xA;install.packages(&amp;quot;gsDesign&amp;quot;) What’s new in gsDesign 3.6.0 Time-to-event endpoint design with calendar timing of analyses We added a gsSurvCalendar() function to enable group sequential design for time-to-event outcomes using calendar specification of interim analysis timing.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
